raise SRTParseError(f"Invalid timestamp line: ")
if len(parts) != 2:
raise SRTParseError(f"Invalid timestamp separator: ")
start_str, end_str = parts
try:
start = cls.parse_timestamp(start_str.strip())
end = cls.parse_timestamp(end_str.strip())
except ValueError as exc:
raise SRTParseError(f"Timestamp parse error: ") from exc
# Combine text lines
text = '\n'.join(text_lines).strip()
if not text:
raise SRTParseError("Empty text after timestamps")
# Truncate text if too long (security) but log warning
if len(text) > MAX_TEXT_LENGTH:
logger.warning(
"Text too long in entry %d (%d chars). Truncating to %d.",
idx, len(text), MAX_TEXT_LENGTH
)
text = text[:MAX_TEXT_LENGTH]
return SubtitleEntry(index=idx, start=start, end=end, text=text)
@classmethod
def parse_srt(cls, content: str) -> List[SubtitleEntry]:
"""
Parse a complete SRT content string into a list of SubtitleEntry objects.
Args:
content: Full SRT subtitle text.
Returns:
List of parsed subtitle entries, in order.
Raises:
SRTParseError: If content is empty or contains invalid blocks.
ValueError: If content exceeds safety limits.
"""
if not content or not content.strip():
raise SRTParseError("SRT content is empty")
# Security: limit maximum input size to prevent DoS
if len(content) > MAX_LINE_LENGTH * MAX_SUBTITLE_ENTRIES:  # approx 200MB
raise ValueError(f"SRT content too large ( chars)")
# Split into blocks using blank lines as separator
raw_blocks = SRT_BLOCK_SEPARATOR.split(content.strip())
entries: List[SubtitleEntry] = []
seen_indices: set = set()
for idx, block in enumerate(raw_blocks, start=1):
if not block.strip():
continue
try:
entry = cls.parse_block(block)
except (SRTParseError, ValueError) as exc:
logger.error("Failed to parse block %d: %s", idx, exc)
continue  # Skip malformed blocks (configurable: could raise)
# Duplicate index check
if entry.index in seen_indices:
logger.warning("Duplicate subtitle index %d detected. Using first occurrence.", entry.index)
continue
seen_indices.add(entry.index)
entries.append(entry)
# Sort by index (optional but good practice)
entries.sort(key=lambda e: e.index)
if not entries:
raise SRTParseError("No valid subtitle entries found in content")
# Safety limit on number of entries
if len(entries) > MAX_SUBTITLE_ENTRIES:
raise ValueError(f"Too many subtitle entries ( > )")
return entries
def srt_to_clean_text(entries: Sequence[SubtitleEntry]) -> str:
"""
Convert list of SubtitleEntry to a clean text representation (plain text).
Args:
entries: Sequence of SubtitleEntry objects.
Returns:
Text content with timestamps removed.
"""
return '\n'.join(entry.text for entry in entries)
# Example usage with the provided SRT content
if __name__ == "__main__":
# Configure logging for demonstration
logging.basicConfig(level=logging.INFO, format='%(asctime)s - %(name)s - %(levelname)s - %(message)s')
logger.info("Starting SRT parsing demo")
# Sample SRT content from security news (as given)
sample_srt = (
"1\n"
"欢迎收看每日安全资讯，\n"
"今天是2026年5月30日。\n"
"\n"
"2\n"
"我是您的主持人，\n"
"今天为您带来最新安全动态。\n"
"\n"
"3\n"
"首先，Oracle发布2026年\n"
"5月关键安全补丁更新，\n"
"\n"
"4\n"
"修复了35个CVE漏洞，\n"
"涉及多个产品线。\n"
"\n"
"5\n"
"其次是关于BLAST后门攻击，\n"
"针对协作多智能体强化学习系统。\n"
"\n"
"6\n"
"这种新型攻击手法\n"
"利用隐蔽后门操纵智能体行为。\n"
"\n"
"7\n"
"接下来我们进行\n"
"30秒的深度解析。\n"
"\n"
"8\n"
"BLAST攻击由知道创宇\n"
"404实验室揭露，\n"
"\n"
"9\n"
"它通过植入恶意时间触发器，\n"
"在特定条件下激活后门。\n"
"\n"
"10\n"
"攻击者可在不破坏\n"
"系统正常运行的前提下，\n"
"\n"
"11\n"
"诱导智能体做出\n"
"有利于攻击者的决策。\n"
"\n"
"12\n"
"这对自动驾驶、金融交易\n"
"等领域的多智能体系统构成威胁。\n"
"\n"
"13\n"
"防御建议包括动态\n"
"信任评分和异构验证。\n"
"\n"
"14\n"
"深度解析结束，\n"
"继续其他资讯。\n"
"\n"
"15\n"
"GuidePoint Security发布\n"
"CMMC合规三步骤指南，\n"
"\n"
"16\n"
"帮助国防供应链企业\n"
"降低网络安全合规门槛。\n"
"\n"
"17\n"
"绿盟科技在资本市场论坛\n"
"解读AI智能体安全治理新范式，\n"
"\n"
"18\n"
"并发布智能体安全创新成果，\n"
"应对高自主执行时代的挑战。\n"
"\n"
"19\n"
"此外，STAR Labs详细分析了\n"
"LiteLLM中四个漏洞链的演变。\n"
"\n"
"20\n"
"这些漏洞允许攻击者\n"
"绕过认证并执行远程代码。\n"
"\n"
"21\n"
"今天的每日安全资讯\n"
"到这里就结束了。\n"
"\n"
"22\n"
"感谢收看，请订阅我们\n"
"获取更多安全动态。\n"
"\n"
"23\n"
"保护系统，从了解威胁开始。\n"
"我们明天再见。"
)
try:
parsed_entries = SRTValidator.parse_srt(sample_srt)
logger.info("Successfully parsed %d subtitle entries.", len(parsed_entries))
for entry in parsed_entries[:3]:
logger.debug("Entry %d: %s -> %s", entry.index, entry.start, entry.end)
# Export clean text
clean = srt_to_clean_text(parsed_entries)
print("=== CLEAN TEXT EXTRACTION ===")
print(clean[:200] + "..." if len(clean) > 200 else clean)
except (SRTParseError, ValueError) as exc:
logger.critical("Fatal SRT parsing error: %s", exc)
raise